Guide to the F. Trubee Davison Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE AND SPEECHES, 1882-1978; Series I; 5 linear feet (12 boxes)
  - Peabody, Endicott
    - Biographical sketches, 1934; 1965 (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - Correspondence, personal, 1937-1939 (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - Documentary film - general correspondence, 1959; 1968-1969, undated (Box 8, Folder 125-126)
    - Documentary Film - letters (photocopies) from Harvard University, 1882 (Box 8, Folder 127)
    - Documentary Film - photographs and negatives, undated (Box 8, Folder 128)
    - Documentary Film - text (narration), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 129)
  - Peabody, Malcolm, 1939-1964 (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Pennoyer, Paul, 1952-1970 (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - Phya, Vidura Dharmabinet, 1949-1971 (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Plantations, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 133)
  - Pleissner, O.M., 1951-1961 (Box 8, Folder 134)
  - Pomeroy, Daniel, 1919; 1924; 1930-1933 (Box 8, Folder 135)
    See also: box 4, folder 72-73
  - Pomeroy, Daniel, 1954-1964 (Box 8, Folder 136)
  - Pomeroy, Daniel - photos, [ca. 1930-1933] (Box 8, Folder 137)
  - Port Washington Police District, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 138)
  - Powell, F.E., 1956-1964 (Box 8, Folder 139)
  - Presbyterian Hospital, 1958-1972 (Box 8, Folder 140)
  - Pyle, Ernest, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 141)
  - Q, 1963-1971 (Box 8, Folder 142)
  - R, 1923-1974 (Box 8, Folder 143)
  - Republican Party - state convention, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 144)
  - Rickenbacker, E.V. (and photos), 1963-1971 (Box 8, Folder 145)
  - Rogers (Will) Memorial Commission, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 146)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 147)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1916; 1918 (Box 9, Folder 148)
  - Roosevelt (Theodore) Association, 1954-1971 (Box 9, Folder 149)
  - S-Sl, 1924-1974 (Box 9, Folder 150)
  - Sm-Sz, 1954-1974 (Box 9, Folder 151)
  - Sagamore Hill Committee (T. Roosevelt), 1949-1964 (Box 9, Folder 152)
  - St. John's (Church.) of Lattington, N.Y., 1954-1972, undated (Box 9, Folder 153)
  - St. Paul's College, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 154)
  - St. Paul's College - printed material and miscellaneous, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 155)
  - Sanford (Leonard C.) Fund, 1951-1972 (Box 9, Folder 156)
  - Seawanhaka Corinthian Yacht Club, 1963-1972 (Box 10, Folder 157)
  - "Seraphics"- secretarial organization, 1952-1965; 1970 (Box 10, Folder 158)
  - Smith, Kenneth L., 1963-1969 (Box 10, Folder 159)
  - Speeches, 1922-1951 (Box 10, Folder 160-163)
  - Speed of birds - research material for article, 1960-1965; 1969 (Box 10, Folder 164)
  - Sperry, Lawrence, Jr. and family, 1966-1974 (Box 10, Folder 165)
  - T, 1933-1972 (Box 10, Folder 166)
  - Thomas, Lowell
    See: box 3, folder 55
  - U, 1966-1973 (Box 10, Folder 167)
  - Unification of the Armed Forces - (Chapter III): "Decline of Interest: 1926-1939" by L.J. Logere, Jr., undated (Box 11, Folder 168)
  - University of the State of New York -Regents Council on the Education Practices Act, 1953-1961 (Box 11, Folder 169)
  - V, 1935-1971 (Box 11, Folder 170)
  - Wa-Wh, 1945-1974 (Box 11, Folder 171)
  - Wi-Wz, 1948-1974 (Box 11, Folder 172)
  - "War Organization of Japan," by Colonel Philip Cole, 1946 January 25 (Box 11, Folder 173)
  - Winthrop, Robert, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 174)
  - Wyandanch Club, 1948-1967 (Box 11, Folder 175)
  - Y-Z, 1938-1972 (Box 11, Folder 176)
  - Yale University
    - Alumni activities, 1946-1948 (Box 11, Folder 177)
    - Alumni activities, 1949; 1953; 1963-1969 (Box 12, Folder 178-179)
    - Class of 1918, 1918; 1941; 1968-1974 (Box 12, Folder 180)
    - Horse Island, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 181)
    - Library (donation of papers), 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 182)
  - Yawkey, Thomas A., 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 183)
  - Unidentified poetry and writings, undated (Box 12, Folder 184)
- FIRST YALE UNIT, 1914-1979; Series II; 5 linear feet (8 boxes)
  The material in this series is divided into the following three sections: Correspondence; Photographs; and Miscellanea.
  These materials include Davison's own correspondence and files as well as items collected from other members of the Yale Unit.
  Correspondence files are alphabetically arranged by correspondent or topic, and include photographs and other enclosures when identifiable.
  Photographs is also an alphabetical arrangement of files. Photographs not relating to the Yale Unit are arranged in SERIES I and III.
  Miscellanea includes printed material and ephemera.
  - Correspondence
    - Aerial Coast Patrol Unit No. 1, 1916-1919, undated (Box 13, Folder 185)
    - Aero Club of America, 1916-1920, undated (Box 13, Folder 186-187)
    - Alcock (John L.) and Company, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 188)
    - Ambulance service, 1916-1919 (Box 13, Folder 189)
    - America Trans Oceanic Company, 1916-1917 (Box 13, Folder 190)
    - Ames, Allen W., 1917-1919; 1950 (Box 13, Folder 191)
    - Beach, C. Frederick, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 192)
    - Brush, Graham M., [ca. 1915-1918] (Box 13, Folder 193)
    - Coombe, Reginald G., 1917-1924, undated (Box 13, Folder 194)
    - Curtiss Aeroplane Motor Company, 1916-1919 (Box 13, Folder 195)
    - Davison, F. Trubee
      - General, 1915-1920; 1924, undated (Box 13, Folder 196-198)
      - Airplane part orders, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 199)
      - Essay, re: history of the Yale Unit, 1919 (Box 14, Folder 200)
      - Military records, 1917-1918 (Box 14, Folder 201)
        See also: box 6, folder 97-98
      - Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 14, Folder 202)
      - Scrapbook (clippings), 1915-1919 (Box 14, Folder 203)
    - Davison, Henry P., 1917 (Box 14, Folder 204)
    - Davison, Henry P., Jr., 1916-1919 (Box 14, Folder 205)
    - Ditman, Albert J., 1916-1918, undated (Box 14, Folder 206)
    - Erie Specialty Company, 1918 (Box 14, Folder 207)
    - Farwell, John V., III, 1917-1919; 1966; undated (Box 14, Folder 208)
    - "Fifty Years After," television tribute to the First Yale Unit, A-Z, 1966-1967 (Box 14, Folder 209)
    - First Yale Unit - publication and distribution of book by Ralph Paine, 1924-1942 (Box 14, Folder 210)
    - Flight logs - for individual pilots, 1917 May-July (Box 14, Folder 211)
    - Fyfe's Shipyard, 1918 (Box 14, Folder 212)
    - Gates, Artemus L. "Di" - includes photos, writings, and miscellaneous papers, 1917-1918, undated (Box 14, Folder 213-217)
    - General Ordinance Company, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 218)
    - Golder, Fred R., 1917-1918 (Box 14, Folder 219)
    - Gould, E.C.B., [ca. 1917-1918] (Box 14, Folder 220)
    - Hammond Radio Research Laboratory, 1916-1917 (Box 15, Folder 221)
    - Huntington, Long Island Base, 1917-1918 (Box 15, Folder 222)
    - Ingalls, David S., 1918-1924; 1968 (Box 15, Folder 223)
    - Ireland, R. Livingston, 1919-1924 (Box 15, Folder 224)
    - James, Oliver B., [ca. 1917-1918] (Box 15, Folder 225)
    - Landon, Henry H., Jr., 1919-1924 (Box 15, Folder 226)
    - Lawrence, G.F., Jr., ("Lotta"), [ca. 1918] (Box 15, Folder 227)
    - Lovett, Robert A., 1917-1919; 1924 (Box 15, Folder 228)
    - Lynch, Francis R. - account of military service, [ca. 1920] (Box 15, Folder 229)
    - McAlpin, Kenneth R., 1917-1918; 1924 (Box 15, Folder 230)
    - McDonnell, Edward O., 1917-1919, undated (Box 15, Folder 231)
    - Macleish, Kenneth, 1918-1925 (Box 15, Folder 232)
    - McIlwaine, K., [ca. 1917] (Box 15, Folder 233)
    - Memorial ceremonies, Huntington Bay, Long Island
      - Clippings and photos, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 234)
      - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 235)
      - Proclamations, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 236)
  - Murdock, Harvey, 1917-1918 (Box 15, Folder 237)
  - Navy Department, 1916-1917, undated (Box 15, Folder 238)
  - Navy League Dinner
    - General, 1966-1968 (Box 15, Folder 239)
    - Congratulations, and narration of slide show, "The F. Trubee Davison Story", 1966 (Box 15, Folder 240)
    - Printed material, photographs, and miscellanea, 1966 -1967 (Box 15, Folder 241)
    - Printed material, Naval Air Reserve Training Command 1916-1966 (Box 16, Folder 242)
  - Peabody, Helen, 1916-1918 (Box 16, Folder 243)
  - Read, Curtis R., [ca. 1917-1924], undated (Box 16, Folder 244)
  - Recruits, [ca. 1917-1918] (Box 16, Folder 245)
  - Rockefeller, William A., 1918 (Box 16, Folder 246)
  - Smith, Kenneth Rose, [ca. 1917-1918] (Box 16, Folder 247)
  - Sperry Gyroscope Company, 1916-1917 (Box 16, Folder 248)
  - Steel Fabricating Company, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 249)
  - Sturtevant, Albert D., [ca. 1917-1918]; 1924 (Box 16, Folder 250)
  - Sullivan, W.F., 1917 (Box 16, Folder 251)
  - Taft, William Howard, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 252)
  - Thompson, Lewis S., 1917-1924 (Box 16, Folder 253)
  - Thompson, William P., II, [ca. 1918] (Box 16, Folder 254)
  - Vorys, John M., [ca. 1917-1918] (Box 16, Folder 255)
  - Walker, Samuel S., 1918; 1924 (Box 16, Folder 256)
  - Willard, Eugene S., 1916-1917 (Box 16, Folder 257)
  - Yale University, 1917-1918 (Box 16, Folder 258)
  - Photographs
    - Album - early aviation photographs of planes and individuals, [ca. 1908-1915] (Box 16, Folder 259)
    - Clippings, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 260)
    - Florida training site, [ca. 1918-1919] (Box 17, Folder 261-262)
    - Foreign aviation, [ca. 1919] (Box 17, Folder 263)
    - Miscellaneous photos, undated (Box 17, Folder 264)
    - Peacock Point, Long Island, [ca. 1916] (Box 17, Folder 265)
  - Slides - Navy League Dinner, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 266)
  - Miscellanea
    - Ground School Manual, Vol. II, U.S. Naval Air Station, Pensacola, Florida, [ca. 1918] (Box 19, Folder 267)
    - Maps - Belgium Coast, 1918 (Box 19, Folder 268)
    - Personnel and payroll records, 1917 April-September (Box 19, Folder 269)
    - "Training Manual, Royal Flying Corps," Part I, 1914 (Box 19, Folder 270)
    - Yale Unit - articles by and about First Yale Unit, [ca. 1918-1979] (Box 19, Folder 271)
    - Yale Unit - dinners, 1930-1931; 1937-1938 (Box 19, Folder 272)
    - Yale Unit - dinners, transcript of remarks, 1924 (Box 19, Folder 273)
    - Yale Unit - miscellaneous, [ca. 1917-1920] (Box 19, Folder 274)
    - Yale Unit - ephemera (compass, dog tags, "wings"), undated (Box 20, Folder 275)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1896-[ca. 1966]; Series III; 5" (1 box)
  Photographs are arranged alphabetically and include scenes of Africa and exhibits at the American Museum of Natural History, members of the Davison family, campaign photos from Davison's political career, and scenes of the Yale crew team.
  Photographs relating to the First Yale Unit are contained in SERIES II.
  - African tribesmen - from M. Akeley, 1926 (Box 21, Folder 276)
  - American Museum of Natural History, [ca. 1935-1950] (Box 21, Folder 277)
  - Children, [ca. 1930-1935] (Box 21, Folder 278)
  - Davison, F. Trubee and Mrs. Helen P. Davison, [ca. 1920-1932] (Box 21, Folder 279)
  - Davison, F. Trubee - portraits, [ca. 1916-1950] (Box 21, Folder 280)
  - Davison, Mrs. Helen P., [ca. 1916-1935] (Box 21, Folder 281)
  - Davison family portraits, [ca. 1920-1930] (Box 21, Folder 282)
  - Hoover, Herbert - with F. Trubee Davison, 1921; 1950 (Box 21, Folder 283)
  - Johnson, Martin - African expedition, [ca. 1933] (Box 21, Folder 284)
  - Miscellaneous, [ca. 1917-1966] (Box 21, Folder 285)
  - Parents and great-grandmother, 1896; 1959 (Box 21, Folder 286)
  - Political campaigns, [ca. 1922-1932] (Box 21, Folder 287)
  - Yale University, [ca. 1916] (Box 21, Folder 288)
- SCRAPBOOKS, 1921-1931; Series IV; 6' (16 boxes)
  This series contains microfilmed scrapbooks, 1-15; 17-48. Volume 16 is missing from the numerical sequence of scrapbooks which does not follow in strict chronological sequence.
  These clippings document Davison's political careers as a state assemblyman from New York, chairman of the National Crime Commission, and Assistant Secretary of War (for Air). Additionally, there are clippings which relate to the Davison family and to the subject of aviation.
  The scrapbooks are filmed in numerical sequence.
  - Volume 1: 1921 Mar 22 - 1924 Aug 14 (Reel 1)
  - Volume 2: 1924 Aug 10 - 1925 Dec 20 (Reel 1)
  - Volume 3: 1925 Dec 20 - 1926 May 6 (Reel 1)
  - Volume 4: 1926 Mar 30 - 1926 Aug 12 (Reel 1)
  - Volume 5: 1926 Aug 12 - 1926 Oct 13 (Reel 1)
  - Volume 6: 1926 Oct 13 - 1927 Jan 23 (Reel 2)
  - Volume 7: 1927 Jan 22 - 1927 Jul 25; Sep 21 (Reel 2)
  - Volume 8: 1927 May 31 - 1927 Aug 6; Oct 18 (Reel 2)
  - Volume 9: 1927 Jun 13 - 1927 Oct 15 (Reel 2)
  - Volume 10: 1927 Sep 28 - 1927 Dec 14 (Reel 2)
  - Volume 11: 1927 Dec 2 - 1928 Mar 26 (Reel 2)
  - Volume 12: 1927 Dec 28 - 1928 Jan 30 (Reel 3)
  - Volume 13: 1928 Jan 17 - 1928 Mar 26 (Reel 3)
  - Volume 14: 1928 Feb 28 - 1928 Apr 13 (Reel 3)
  - Volume 15: 1928 Feb 21 - 1928 Apr 9 (Reel 3)
  - Volume 16: MISSING (Reel 3)
  - Voume 17: 1928 Mar 13 - 1928 Aug 3 (Reel 3)
  - Volume 18: 1928 Apr 6 - 1928 Jun 28; Sep 23 (Reel 3)
  - Volume 19: 1928 Apr 11 - 1928 Jun 19 (Reel 4)
  - Volume 20: 1928 May 12 - 1928 Oct 12 (Reel 4)
  - Volume 21: 1928 Jun 26 - 1928 Sep 13 (Reel 4)
  - Volume 22: 1928 Jul 30 - 1929 Feb 22 (Reel 4)
  - Volume 23: 1928 May; 1928 Sep 20 - 1929 Jan 29 (Reel 4)
  - Volume 24: 1928 Oct 12 - 1929 Feb 26 (Reel 4)
  - Volume 25: 1927 Mar 3 - 1929 Feb 24 (Reel 4)
  - Volume 26: 1928 Dec 18 - 1929 Jan 16 (Reel 5)
  - Volume 27: 1929 Jan 8 - 1929 Mar (Reel 5)
  - Volume 28: 1929 Jul 14 -1929 Sep 30; Nov 6 (Reel 5)
  - Volume 29: 1929 Mar 18 - 1929 Aug 30; Oct 24; Nov 11 (Reel 5)
  - Volume 30: 1929 Apr 24 - 1929 Aug 9; Sep 5; Oct 6 (Reel 5)
  - Volume 31: 1929 May 31 - 1929 Oct 27; Nov 30 (Reel 5)
  - Volume 32: 1929 Jul 25 - 1930 Jan 8 (Reel 5)
  - Volume 33: 1929 Sep 3 - 1929 Dec 30 (Reel 5)
  - Volume 34: 1929 Oct 30 - 1929 Dec 30 (1930 Jan 1-17?) (Reel 6)
  - Volume 35: 1929 Nov 30 - 1930 Feb 4 (Reel 6)
  - Volume 36: 1929 Feb 28 - 1930 Jan 26 (Reel 6)
  - Volume 37: 1929 Feb 27 - 1930 Feb 15 (Reel 6)
  - Volume 38: 1929 Nov 24 - 1930 Nov 29 (Reel 6)
  - Volume 39: 1930 Feb 4 - 1930 Aug 26 (Reel 6)
  - Volume 40: 1930 Jan 18 - 1930 Aug 31 (Reel 6)
  - Volume 41: 1930 Feb 18 - 1931 Jan 14 (Reel 6)
  - Volume 42: 1930 May 3 - 1931 Jan 24 (Reel 6)
  - Volume 43: 1930 May 14 - 1930 Sep 26 (Reel 7)
  - Volume 44: 1930 Aug 12 - 1930 Nov 25 (Reel 7)
  - Volume 45: 1930 Sep 22 - 1930 Nov 3 (Reel 7)
  - Volume 46: 1930 Sep 17 - 1931 Jan 25 (Reel 7)
  - Volume 47: 1930 Sep 18 - 1931 Jan 26; 1930 Feb 9 - 1930 May 31 (Reel 7)
  - Volume 48: 1929 Dec 8 - 1931 Jan 29 (Reel 7)